Christopher French

Kansas City, MO | Website | LinkedIn

Summary:

Full-stack developer with an emphasis on automation, data engineering, and analytics using Python and Node. Worked in several industries -- GIS, logistics, medical insurance -- at companies like Microsoft, Esri, and C.H. Robinson. Experience with building back-end systems in the cloud (Azure, AWS, Spark, Glue) and front-end design (React/Gatsby/Next.js). Created and maintained microservices and pipelines.

Enjoys to program and build systems, is understanding, always willing to listen to ideas, and enjoys working with a team of likewise individuals.

Expertise:

- **Data Engineering:** Python, SQL, ETL jobs using Airflow and cron jobs in linux, cloud, and Docker environments, data mungering and processing
- Full Stack Developer: Flask, FastAPI, Django, Blazer/.NET Framework, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch, React, Gatsby
- Cloud & Automation: Azure, AWS, Vault, Linux, CI/CD pipelines, Batch scripting, Kafka
- **Machine Learning:** Foundations of statistics, data analysis using NumPy/Pandas, data visualization, ChatGPT and tools like scipy
- **Technical Writing:** Static-site generation, Markdown, XML, photo-editing, creating data pipelines to build documentation, writing developer guides and code samples
- Tools: Git, CMake/Scons, Linux, Docker, Unreal Engine 4/5, Godot, Visual Studio

Primary Programming Languages:

- Scripting: Python, Node/Typescript, Bash
- APIs: Python, Node, C#/.NET Framework
- Web: JS/TypeScript, Python, CSS, HTML, JSX, HTML-templating (e.g. Nunjucks, Jinja2)
- Systems: C, modern C++ (17), C#, Rust
- Misc: GDScript, LaTeX, OCaml, NetLogo, R

Professional Experience

Python Developer - C.H. Robinson (Freight Quote, Contractor), Kansas City, MO

July 2023 - Current

- Built and designed a new company-wide CRM app for sales representatives in Typescript and FastAPI, with a PostgreSQL backend -- hosted in Azure (Backstage/Helm/Terraform)
- Maintained React websites in React with Django as the backend

- · Maintained services running in VMs using Docker
- APIs maintained and updated using FastAPI and PosgreSQL

Machine Learning Engineer I - Spring Venture Group, Kansas City, MO

Feb 2022 - Mar 2023

- Leveraged AWS for the development of microservices with FastAPI/Flask.
- Utilized AWS services including Batch, ECS, Airflow, RDS (MySQL), Redis, Redshift (Postgres), Lambdas, and AWS CDK to create analytics pipelines and lead ingestion.
- Instrumented and logged data using Splunk and Datadog.
- Worked collaboratively with data scientists to integrate business logic with ML models.

Data Engineer II - Spring Venture Group, Kansas City, MO

Sep 2020 - Feb 2022

- Crafted ETL jobs in Python using AWS Batch, PySpark, and Airflow.
- Authored and optimized SQL queries, interfacing with AWS RDS and Redshift databases.
- Programmed AWS Glue jobs and created Glue tables for querying in Athena.

GIS Analyst - AmeriCorps Vista, Kansas City, KS

May 2020 - Sep 2020

• Authored GIS ETL tasks in Python using ArcGIS Pro and geopandas/PostGIS.

Product Engineer & Technical Writer - Esri, Portland, OR

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

- Planned and wrote developer documentation for a new REST API-based PaaS.
- Developed documentation automation tools in Node, wrote developer guides and tutorials.

Technical Writer, Programmer - Microsoft (via Pactera), Bellevue, WA

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018

- Migrated documentation from MSDN to Microsoft Docs using Markdown and OpenAPI specs.
- Authored code samples in C# and HTML/JS, maintained the Bing Maps .NET SDK Toolkit.

Data Analyst and Programmer - Pactera, Redmond, WA

Mar 2017 - Dec 2018

Developed analytics, billing, and judge quality control tools in Python and .NET (C#/WPF).

Tutor - Huntington Learning Center, Bellevue, WA

Apr 2017 - Nov 2017

• Tutored students for the ACT and SAT, as well as AP Computer Science and Calculus.

Contributing Editor - Gumstix, Inc., Vancouver, BC

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

• Authored content using WordPress, JS, Bootstrap, and HTML/CSS.

Education

Ph.D. Philosophy, 2008-2015

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada

- Emphasis on the **history and philosophy of science**, especially probability theory, inductive logic, and history of analytical philosophy
- Courses in the foundations of probability theory, cognitive science, history of science, philosophy of biology, philosophy of the social sciences (especially decision theory and game theory), early modern and modern philosophy (esp. Hobbes, Kant, and neo-Kantians like Cassirer and Helmholtz), value theory, and analytical philosophy (Rudolf Carnap, Hans Reichenbach, Karl Popper, Bertrand Russell, Frege)

B.A. in Philosophy, 2003-2008

Kansas State University, Manhattan, Kansas, United States

- Minor in Computer Science (courses used C, OCaml, Java, and Python)
- **GPA:** 3.5
- Math courses included: Calc 1-3, Differential Equations, Discrete Math, Topology, Intro to probability and stats